Alex Matsarski

JavaScript/Groovy Grails Developer - Gamgee Inc

Dublin, CA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Alex-Matsarski/8da5e2a75de4721d

Goal-oriented, dynamic professional with over 4 years of experience in full life cycle projects involving analysis, design, development, deployment, testing, documentation, implementation and maintenance of applications in Web-based environment and Distributed n-tier architecture.

Excellent proficiency in Java/J2EE and Groovy technologies including Grails, Hibernate, Spring and Struts frameworks with MVC design Patterns.

Expert in JavaScript, HTML 5, CSS.

Expert in iOS development.

Strong expertise in web frameworks such as JQuery, Backbone, Require.

Experience in relational databases such as MySQL.

Strong team player with ability to work productively in a team as well as individually.

Proven time management skills, strong work ethic.

WORK EXPERIENCE

JavaScript/Groovy Grails Developer

Gamgee Inc - San Mateo, CA - April 2013 to Present

Gamgee Inc. develops mobile application to help patients to prepare for various medical procedures and tests. In this project my role is to built Content Management Tools and server side API for our Content Team. Using my tools Content Team has possibilities to create, edit and delete related content such as text, images and sounds. Afterwards this related content is used in frond-end mobile application. In Server side I use Groovy and Grails technologies, in front-end - JavaScript, HTML5, CSS as well as a bunch of JavaScript frameworks and libraries described above.

Responsibilities:

Building the web application using JavaScript, HTML, CSS;

Developing server-side using Java, Groovy;

Developing iOS application.

Creating and configuring data base structure;

Implementing Junit and Spock tests for server API as well as Qunit tests for JavaScript code;

Maintaining deployment and update of Grails project on the server (Amazon);

Introducing new features and interfaces for Content Team and improving the product after receiving bugs and user experience feedback.

Environment: Eclipse, xCode, SourceTree, Redmine, Jenkins.

Java/JEE Developer

The Community Systems, Inc - Palo Alto, CA - December 2011 to February 2013

Built an iPhone mobile application for a social networking based reservation system. The application caters to the owners of businesses such as restaurants, hospitals etc. as well as to the customers of these businesses. Using this application business owners are able to upload their schedules to the server-side application, manage the employees schedules. Customers can make reservations in businesses such as restaurants, hospitals, automobile shops etc. Customers have the possibility to rate the business services while ratings and reviews will be published for other users. The company is a startup.

Responsibilities:

Built the web application using JavaScript, HTML, CSS;

Built the mobile application using Objective-C and xCode;

Developed RESTful interfaces for the web application. Data provided by these interfaces was consumed by the mobile application as well as the third-party applications;

Used Spring for dependency injection and transaction management;

Configured dependencies using both XML and Annotations;

Implemented Data access layer, using Hibernate as ORM;

Used HQL to retrieve data from the db;

Integrated Spring with Hibernate for transaction management;

Worked on bug fixing, enhancements, testing and deployment of the application;

Participated in Code Reviews;

Involved in Handling Staging and Production Issues;

Implemented logging and tracing using Log4j.

Environment Eclipse, xCode.

Internship, Java Developer

EPAM Systems Inc - Минск - May 2011 to October 2011

EPAM Systems is a reputed software services and solutions company with the offices in Europe and USA. Worked on a railroad ticket purchase system. The application is used by ticket selling agents for railroad companies.

Responsibilities:

Captured specifications from user requirements and modeled Sequence Diagrams, Class Diagrams complaint to UML standards;

Used the Struts2 validations for validating form data:

Created tile definitions, struts config files, validation files and resource bundles for Admin Domain module using Struts2 framework;

Developed web tier using Struts tag libraries, CSS, HTML, XML, JSP and Servlets;

Implemented internationalization (I18N) of the web application.

Environment: Eclipse.

Internship, Java Developer

The University of the Belarus Industry Department - Минск - June 2010 to February 2011

Built a truck management application as a part of the internship. The application allowed users to schedule truck maintenance and repairs, assign schedules to drivers and manage inventory.

Responsibilities:

Designed and coded HTML screens;

Designed and developed the UI using JSP, HTML, CSS and JavaScript;

Extensively worked on Java server side programming using Servlets and JSP;

Gathered requirements, working with end users of the application.

Environment: Eclipse.

Mechanic Engineer

Alutech Inc - Минск - August 2007 to May 2010

The Alutech Group is one of the leading European suppliers of roller shutter systems and sectional doors.

Responsibilities:

Organized the transport supply line;

Arranged vehicles and trucks maintenance and repair (both in-house and third-party service);

Organized and provided transportation as a licensed activity;

Number of subordinates - 17 people (vehicles technical serviceability subordination).

EDUCATION

BS in Computer Science

The University of the Belarus Industry Department - Минск

BS in Mechanical Engineering

Military Academy - Минск

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

SKILLS:

Groovy, Java, Javascript, Objective-C, SQL

JSP2.x, JSF 2.X, Servlet2.3/2.4, JDBC2.0, JNDI1.2, RMI, JAXB, DTD, SAX, DOM, JSTL, JAX-WS, JAX-RS, Swing

jQuery, jQuery-UI, jQury-Mobile, QUnit, Sinon, Backbone, Require, Underscore, Famous (beginning)

Grails, Spring 2.x/3.x, Hibernate 3.x, JPA, Struts2, JUnit, Spock

Tomcat 6.x/7.x, AWS.

Google Maps API, Google Drive API, Dropbox Drive API

MySQL 5.x

HTML5, CSS, AJAX, JSON

Git, Subversion, Jenkins, Redmine

Mac OS X, Windows 7/Vista, Ubuntu Linux

Eclipse, xCode